# Mario Altagracia Jimenez

1908 Willow Creek Dr | Austin, TX | 512-994-1887 | Jimernez.io@gmail.com | Github.com/Toughee

# **Summary**

4 years of freelance programming experience for government and media industry. Dedicated web developer focused on front end development. Experienced in building web applications emphasizing on responsive design. Able to work and adjust myself in any team environment. Capable of learning any tool or software needed complete any work assigned.

# **Experience**

Help Desk Agent

Nov 2017 – Present

Holiday Inn Express

Austin, TX

Onsite Tech support for hotel guests and clients staying inside the hotel.

- Resolved daily troubleshooting and networking issues
- Configured connectivity, WLAN, and I.P. issues for Apple products
- Helped 90% of hotel guest's with their connectivity issues in a 7 month period.
- Environment: macOS, iOS, Windows 8

Web Developer

Nov 2016 – June 2017

Code for America Durham, NC

Collaborative volunteer position for the City of Durham and the Government of North Carolina.

• Resolved U/I issues and refined U/X for the web application

- Managed to launch complete application for public use before deadline.
- Regularly collaborated with a small team to resolve project issues
- Environment: Ruby on rails, Adobe creative suite, Github, Docker

#### Founder and UI Developer

November 2013 - May 2014

Sx3 Consulting Firm

San Juan, P.R

Independent startup company focused on media and entertainment industry. Collaborated with a national media platform to produce weekly client work.

- Achieved highest viewer ratings in company's website from client work
- Created successful branding strategies for different clients
- Environment: Adobe Creative Suite, Final Cut Pro

### **Technical Skills**

Web languages: HTML, CSS3, Python, HTML5, JavaScript

Frameworks / Libraries: Bootstrap, Django, React

Version Control: Git

**Servers and Databases:** PostgresSQL, Node.js, npm, Docker **Operating Systems:** Windows 8, Windows 10, macOS, Linux/Unix

**Desktop Publishing Software:** Adobe Creative Suite

Collaboration tools: Slack, Github

## **Education**

**Sacred Heart University** 

B.A in **Advertising**Aug 2011 – May 2016

### **Personal Interests**

Machine learning, Open Software, Engineering, A.I, Computer Networking, Drone technology, Science Fiction novels,